{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"James Cagney","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Mitchum","Bruce Willis","Mel Gibson"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Tom Powers in The Public Enemy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Me And Mrs. Jones","incorrectAnswers":["Two of Hearts","Round And Round","Tainted Love"],"question":"What song did Billy Paul have a hit with in 1972?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Pilgrims","incorrectAnswers":["Conquistadors","Explorers","Traders"],"question":"Who sailed to the new world in The Mayflower?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Germany","Latvia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Novosibirsk?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three equal vertical bands of green white and red.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal horizontal bands of red white and black.","Red with a green five-pointed star in the center.","Red field with a yellow sun in the center."],"question":"What does the flag of Italy look like?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Taekwondo","incorrectAnswers":["Karate","Judo","Muay Thai"],"question":"Which of these is a Korean martial art?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Strand pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Shaped pasta","Soup pasta","Stuffed pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is capellini?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saudi Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand","Mexico","Israel"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Al-Hijr Archaeological Site?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The story of a mobster, covering his relationship with his wife and his mob partners.","incorrectAnswers":["A woman works with a hardened boxing trainer to become a professional.","A secretary checks into a remote motel run by a young man under the domination of his mother.","In World War II a group of soldiers go behind enemy lines to rescue a paratrooper."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Goodfellas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Manila","incorrectAnswers":["Georgetown","Windhoek","Porto-Novo"],"question":"What is the capital city of Philippines?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Michelangelo","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo","Raphael","Donatello"],"question":"By what name is the great italian sculptor & artist Buonarroti better known?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"There's no place like home.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\"","\"I’m already pregnant. So, what other shenanigans could I get myself into?\"","\"This is the day you will always remember as the day you almost caught Captain Jack Sparrow!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Wizard of Oz'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Wong","incorrectAnswers":["Loki","Steve Rogers","Nick Fury"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Benedict Wong?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Boxing","Cricket","Tennis"],"question":"With which sport is Paavo Nurmi associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Glaucoma","incorrectAnswers":["Cataracts","Myopia","Astigmatism"],"question":"What medical term is often caused by abnormally high fluid pressure in the eye?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Wrocław","incorrectAnswers":["Prague","Hamburg","Geneva"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Poland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kyiv","incorrectAnswers":["Sofia","Belgrade","Kharkiv"],"question":"What is the capital city of Ukraine?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ligature","incorrectAnswers":["Binder","Cautoriser","Bandina"],"question":"What is the word for a thread used in surgery to tie a bleeding blood vessel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pole Vaulting","incorrectAnswers":["Golf","Curling","Sumo"],"question":"Which sport requires a planting box?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dialects","incorrectAnswers":["X-Rays","Drugs","Clouds"],"question":"What is dialectology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Luxembourg","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","United Kingdom","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cuspid","incorrectAnswers":["Molar","Incisor","Premolar"],"question":"What is another name for a canine tooth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tom Jones","incorrectAnswers":["Adele","Shirley Bassey","Duran Duran"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film Thunderball?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Red wine","incorrectAnswers":["Whiskey","Beer","Ouzo"],"question":"What type of alcohol is traditionally used in the Greek dish 'Moussaka'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"An assist","incorrectAnswers":["A help","A pair","A lead"],"question":"In basketball, what is recorded on the scoresheet to credit a helpful pass resulting in a score?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Geoffrey Chaucer","incorrectAnswers":["Bede","William Wordsworth","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Who wrote \"The Canterbury Tales\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rammstein","incorrectAnswers":["Cascada","Blue System","Scorpions"],"question":"Which German industrial metal band released the single 'Du hast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bosnia & Herzegovina","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Argentina","Estonia"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of Mostar?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Søren Kierkegaard","incorrectAnswers":["Ludwig Wittgenstein","Epictetus","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The function of prayer is not to influence God, but rather to change the nature of the one who prays'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North Korea","incorrectAnswers":["Mongolia","Japan","Vietnam"],"question":"Pyongyang is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Lupita Nyong'o","incorrectAnswers":["Sally Hawkins","Jennifer Lawrence","Julia Roberts"],"question":"Who won the 2013 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Patsey in 12 Years a Slave?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Mannerism","Modernism"],"question":"The painting \"Landscape with the Fall of Icarus\" by Pieter Bruegel the Elder is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Crimean War","incorrectAnswers":["World War II","The Vietnam War","The Hundred Years War"],"question":"In which war did Florence Nightingale earn her reputation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Two of Hearts","incorrectAnswers":["Heart And Soul","Tainted Love","Lovin' You"],"question":"Stacey Q had a one hit wonder in 1986 with which song?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Boyle's Law","incorrectAnswers":["Dalton's Law","Charles's Law","Gay-Lussac's Law"],"question":"What is the name of the chemistry law stating that the pressure of a gas at constant temperature varies inversely with its volume?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Grapefruit ","incorrectAnswers":["Lemon","Blood Orange","Orange"],"question":"What is common name for the fruit Citrus Grandis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Nightmare Before Christmas","incorrectAnswers":["Edward Scissorhands","Batman","Corpse Bride"],"question":"The Character Jack Skellington Appears In Which 1993 Tim Burton Film?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Midnight Hour","incorrectAnswers":["Midnight Sonata","Midnight Train to Georgia","Midnight Cowboy"],"question":"What was Wilson Pickett's first solo top 40 hit, released in 1965?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Heteronyms","incorrectAnswers":["Homonyms","Synonyms","Antonyms"],"question":"Which term refers to words that are spelled the same but have different sounds and neanings?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White with a red and blue yin yang symbol in the center.","incorrectAnswers":["Three equal vertical bands of green white and orange.","Blue with a yellow cross extending to the edges.","Red with a white crescent moon and star."],"question":"What does the flag of South Korea look like?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Panama","incorrectAnswers":["Pakistan","Paraguay","Palau"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.pa' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Southeast Asia","incorrectAnswers":["South America","China","Africa"],"question":"Where in the world are tangerines originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Uzbekistan","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Iceland","Central African Republic"],"question":"Tashkent is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Submarine","incorrectAnswers":["The Torpedo","TNT","The Tank"],"question":"Designed By Robert Fulton, Which Weapon Was Tested In The Seine In 1801?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"64","incorrectAnswers":["100","8","50"],"question":"What number is the binary 1000000 equal to?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cricket","incorrectAnswers":["Volleyball","Badminton","Ice Hockey"],"question":"With which sport is Shane Warne associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'The Final Cut'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Marie Curie","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Stephen Hawking","Francis Crick"],"question":"Who is the only person two win two nobel prizes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Brain","incorrectAnswers":["Skin","Heart","Lungs"],"question":"What does encephalitis affect?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Elephant Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Zodiac Killer","The Red Baron","Vanilla Ice"],"question":"Who was Joseph Merrick?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Portugal","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","Pakistan","Gabon"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.pt' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"TNT","incorrectAnswers":["QuickSilver","Dry Ice","Borax"],"question":"What is trinitrotoluene commonly known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Lichtenstein","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","San Marino","Luxembourg"],"question":"Holy Roman Emperor Charles VI created which principality in 1719?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aerosmith","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'I Don't Want to Miss a Thing'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Tin","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Silver","Bronze"],"question":"In western societies, what is the traditional gift for a 10th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Bandy","incorrectAnswers":["Korfball","Kabaddi","Jereed"],"question":"Which of these is a traditional Russian sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mercury","incorrectAnswers":["Mars","Jupiter","Saturn"],"question":"Which planet is never observable when the sky is fully dark?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Fergie","incorrectAnswers":["Gaga","RiRi","Bey"],"question":"What is the name of the woman from The Black Eyed Peas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Gravy","incorrectAnswers":["Salt","Bread","Cheese"],"question":"On a dinner table, what item might served in a 'boat'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Propane","incorrectAnswers":["Methane","Hydrogen","Acetylene"],"question":"Instead of charcoal, what gas in a tank might you use to fuel a barbecue?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Marseille","incorrectAnswers":["Real Madrid","FC Schalke","Manchester United"],"question":"Which team won the first UEFA Champions League in 1992?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"T. Rex","incorrectAnswers":["Queen","Talking Heads","Black Sabbath"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album \"Electric Warrior\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Poland","Portugal","Tunisia"],"question":"Where is the Blue Grotto?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kill Bill: Vol. 1","incorrectAnswers":["Million Dollar Baby","Unforgiven","Dead Poets Society"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'After awakening from a coma, a former assassin wreaks vengeance on those who betrayed her.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An Army officer serving in Vietnam is tasked with assassinating a renegade Special Forces Colonel.","incorrectAnswers":["A tramp who has fallen in love with a blind flower girl saves money to help her medically.","A freed slave sets out to rescue his wife from a brutal plantation-owner.","A Scottish warrior leads his countrymen in a rebellion to free his homeland."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Apocalypse Now?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ernest Hemmingway","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Conrad","Anthony Burgess","George Orwell"],"question":"Whose first collection of short stories entitled \"In Our Time\" was published in 1925?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["France","Germany","Spain"],"question":"Which country won the 2002 FIFA World Cup, hosted in South Korea & Japan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"IMAX","incorrectAnswers":["Motorola","Nokia","Sony"],"question":"'Think big' is a slogan associated with which technology brand?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Algiers","incorrectAnswers":["Oran","Constantine","Rabat"],"question":"What is the capital of Algeria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mount Fuji","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Yari","Mount Ontake","Mount Hakusan"],"question":"What is the name of the highest mountain in Japan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sarah Paulson","incorrectAnswers":["Keira Knightley","Naomi Watts","Salma Hayek"],"question":"Which actress has appeared in films including American Horror Story and 12 Years a Slave?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Middle Ages","incorrectAnswers":["Classical Period","Dark Ages","Age of Exploration"],"question":"What is the name given to the period of European history prior to the Renaissance?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chicago Whitesox","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago Orioles","Chicago Reds","Chicago Stars"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Atlas Shrugged","incorrectAnswers":["Brave New World","Fahrenheit 451","1984"],"question":"In which novel does a character called John Galt persuade the world's business leaders to abandon their companies and form a new capitalist society?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"waves or wave motions","incorrectAnswers":["weather","Tibet","mental processes in living creatures"],"question":"What is Kymatology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight","Divergent"],"question":"In which book series does 'Ron Weasley' appear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Opossum","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Coyote","Otter"],"question":"Name the only native North American marsupial?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gregor Mendel","incorrectAnswers":["Alexander Graham Bell","Thomas Edison","Charles Darwin"],"question":"Who is known as the father of genetics?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["White","Maroon","Green"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Germany?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Devil worshipers","incorrectAnswers":["Microscopic objects","South America","The nature of value judgements"],"question":"What is chavezology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bell-bottoms","incorrectAnswers":["Cargo pants","Three-quarter lengths","Trumpet pants"],"question":"What type of flared pants were popular during the era of disco music?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Warm air moving up fast","incorrectAnswers":["Earthquakes","Ozone touching cloud","Clouds at high altitudes"],"question":"Which of these can cause a thunderstorm?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Hungary","Austria","Slovenia"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Poland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2003","incorrectAnswers":["1997","2000","2006"],"question":"In which year was Kill Bill: Vol. 1 first released in the cinema?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Mayfair","incorrectAnswers":["Kensington","Trafalgar Square","Old Kent Road"],"question":"What Is The Most Valuble Property In A Game Of British Monopoly?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Ukraine","Tajikistan","Belarus"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Karachi?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Tom","incorrectAnswers":["A Rooster","A Boar","A Buck"],"question":"A male cat is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Busan","incorrectAnswers":["Hanoi","Manila","Petaling Jaya"],"question":"Which of these cities is in South Korea?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Stuffed pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Strand pasta","Tubular pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is tortellini?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Indo-European","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Afroasiatic","Niger–Congo"],"question":"The language 'Sindhi' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["China","The USA","Australia"],"question":"Which country has the largest amount of timezones on its mainland?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A parliament","incorrectAnswers":["A host","A nest","A yoke"],"question":"What is the word for a group of owls?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mars","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Uranus","Venus"],"question":"Phobos and Deimos are the moons of which planet?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sulfuric acid","incorrectAnswers":["Salt","Water","Coal"],"question":"Which substance has the chemical formula H2SO4?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Luddites","incorrectAnswers":["Antitechs","Weavos","Resisters"],"question":"What Was The Name Given To Textile Workers Who Opposed Modernisation During The Nineteenth Century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Thor","incorrectAnswers":["Odin","Baldur","Heimdall"],"question":"Who is the Norse god of thunder and war?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"A martial art","incorrectAnswers":["A watersport","A racquet sport","A ball game"],"question":"What type of sport is muay thai, a popular sport in Asia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ron Howard","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed A Beautiful Mind?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Aminiotic Fluid","incorrectAnswers":["Birth Fluid","Placental Fluid","Grow Juice"],"question":"What Is The Fluid Which Surrounds A Foetus Known As?","difficulty":"medium"},